All right. So, I showed you why when
you're storing information that you want
to access by name, why an object might
be better. Um, because I showed you that
if you um rearrange
uh the information, then it can get put
into the wrong order when you do an
array destructuring.
Um whereas when you destructure an
object, they are already assigned by
name and therefore you're not going to
pull them out in the wrong order. her
first name isn't going to end up with
alias inside of it. Well, storing
objects in arrays is something we fairly
commonly want to do. What I'm going to
do here is I'm going to uncopy this
array. I'm sorry, uncomment this array.
Okay, so I have an array. It has arrays
in it. That's not what I want. I
actually want this array to have objects
in it. Well, and I kind of want them to
look like this. Well, fortunately, there
is a built-in method to do it. And this
is the last array method that I'll cover
for now. Um so the way this works is we
can say justice um let new justice
league equal justice league dom
here it takes a function. Do you
remember when I made you write a
function called apply to array where it
took in a function that you wanted to
apply and it applied it to the entire
array to make changes to the array?
Well, I'm sorry. Confession time. That
already existed. It's called the map
function. I made you write it because I
wanted you to get experience with
functions and looping and arrays, but it
actually already exists. It's called the
map function. So, what map does is it
says, give me a function and I will
apply it to every single item in this
array. Well, let's write that function.
Um, it's going to take in a value which
is going to be an item in the array. So
in this case, I'm going to call each
item in this array is a list and each
list is a superhero. So I'm going to say
let's take a superhero
out of the array.
And then I'm going to write a lambda
function because it's going to be on
multiple lines. I'm going to use curly
braces.
So now I'm writing a function. Um
hopefully you recognize this syntax for
writing a function. And what do I want
to do? Well, I want to dstructure that
superhero. So, I'm going to say let
first last
alias
numbum villains
equal
the superhero.
Okay. Then I want to turn that into an
object. So, I'm going to say let um
superhero
object equal and then I'm going to do
curly braces and I'm going to say first
name
first name and I'm going to put in first
right here
and then I'm going to put a comma and
I'm going to say last name and I'm going
to store last. And then I'm gonna say
alias.
And I'm going to put in this alias right
here.
And then I'm gonna say
numbum
villains caught. And I am going to store
this num villains variable. Okay, that
creates an object. But we want to put
that object into the new array that
we're creating. So in order to do that,
we write return. And what are we
returning? We're returning the superhero
object.
So, let's save this. And I'm in our
console.log, our new Justice League.
If we save it
and we come over to our console, we
reload our page.
Um, okay. If we hover over Justice
League, it has a bunch of arrays in it
and it took superhero out of the array.
Superhero was one array with Clark,
Kent, Superman, and 12. Now we're going
to dstructure that array. So now it put
Clark into first, Kent into last, alias
into Superman, and number of villains
into 12. Now we're going to create a
superhero object out of that. If we hit
next, our superhero object has four
definitions and four values. We call
these keys and we call these values. So
alias is storing Superman, first name is
storing Clark, last name is storing
Kent, and num villains caught is storing
12. Now we're going to return that
object
and we're going to start over. So now
we've pulled in the second item which is
Bruce Wayne Batman. And I am going to
speed this up and go until this next
breakpoint. So I'm going to remove this
breakpoint and hit continue. Once we're
done, if we look at our new Justice
League, it is storing a bunch of
objects. No longer is it storing a bunch
of arrays. It's storing objects, which
means we can pull things out of those
objects by name. To test this out, let's
go to the console. I'm going to copy the
name of our new array. So I'm going to
paste it here. Say new Justice League
at the zero position. And let's just hit
enter. And you can hopefully see here
that it is an object with first name
Clark, last name Kent, alias Superman,
number villains caught 12. So if I say
new Justice League at the zero position
first name, it should print out Clark.
Sure enough, there it is. If we print
out dot alias,
we can see that it's Superman. So what
we could do is we can now loop through
this Justice League array and then print
out everything by first name.ast name
alias and num villain Scott.
And so what you can see is we were able
to successfully apply a function
to this Justice League array to create a
new array
that's been adjusted. So we took in an
array filled with arrays. We took in
each array, converted it into an object,
and put it into the new array. The new
array is here. So, map takes in a
function, applies it to an entire array,
and creates a new array that you can
store. And that covers our video on dot